退下
Debounce.
如果你从没想过它是如何运作的或是自动完成的
If you've never thought about how
it works or an autocomplete, or
我不知道任何类型的解决方案，我们会了解现在的情况。
I don't know any type of head solution,
we're gonna learn how now.
如果你有这个可能有点棘手因为很难
If you have this probably, it's
a little trickier because it's hard to
如果你从来没有考虑过的话
mentally picture if you've
never given any consideration.
我们去解决这个问题
Let's go and solve this one.
这个我知道我一直说他们都有点棘手
This one, I know I keep saying
they're all little tricky,
我觉得这些都有点棘手
cuz I consider these all a little tricky.
我永远不会说这个很容易
I'll never say this one's an easy one.
也许倒转一个绳子也不是，那是个好的热身问题。
Maybe reversing a string was not too,
that's a good warm up question.
但如果你从来没考虑过这个就有点棘手了
But this one is a little tricky
if you've never considered it.
我们去把它输入出去
Let's go and type it out.
所以我们要做的就是签名
So debounce, what we're gonna do is
the signature would look something
就像 debunce，感谢你的自动完成，它能及时地发挥作用。
like debounce, thank you autocomplete,
and it would take a function in time.
这意味着，每次我要调用此函数时，请说其他函数。
That means every time I wanna invoke this
function later, say some other function.
函数 1，如果我想稍后调用它，它会在此处触发。
Function 1, if I wanna invoke it later,
it'll fire here.
但是我要做的才不会真正执行我想做的事情
But it won't actually execute what I
wanted to do until the time has passed
足够了
sufficiently.
在头部的类型中，让我们说 mdn，
So again in the type of head,
let's say mdn,
我们之前在看平面地图
we're looking at flat map earlier.
如果我们在做一些像取结果一样的东西，我们就不希望像我那样
If we're doing something like say fetching
results, we wouldn't want as I type along,
一百万次的要求
a million requests going out.
我们只想在我停止打字的时候才这样做
We'd only wanna do it
when I've stopped typing.
然后，该功能实际执行。
And then the function actually executes.
一旦我们完成了我就会给你展示如何实施油门
And once we're done with this I'll
show you how to implement throttle,
这有点不一样
which is a little different.
这意味着
Which means,
当我们输入时它将会触发第一个但它不会触发后续的
as we type, it'll fire the first one but
it won't fire the subsequent ones.
然后它就会等到第一次发射
And then it'll wait and
then it'll fire the first one and
烧了以后的吧
fire the subsequent ones.
Versus debunce 希望我能解释清楚
Versus debounce, which hopefully
if I've explained it correctly,
一旦你做了就会被开除
it will fire once you're
done doing the thing.
所以每当有新动作出现时，如果事件列表再次触发，
So every time a new action comes in, say
that event list fires again, it's gonna
在能够执行之前停止先前的执行，然后等待。
stop the previous executions before
they were able to execute and then wait.
它会一直等到它完成
It's gonna wait until it's done.
好吧我知道我说了很多让我们开始行动吧
All right, I know I talked a lot,
so let's implement debounce.
再一次，它是一个功能。
So again, it's a function.
我认为今天的一切都是一个功能。
I think everything today
has been a function.
还有其他的功能和时间
And it's gonna take some
other function and time.
前面的例子是我们想要放弃的功能。
And that earlier example,
we want debounced function.
我们要执行这一命令
And we're gonna wanna execute that.
因此，请指出这是事件侦听器或类似的事件。
So, say this is in an event listener or
something like that.
那是什么把戏
So, what's the trick?
如果它是你以后要执行的功能
If it's a function that
you're gonna execute later,
你一定会想回去的
you're going to at some point
wanna return that function.
好吧我们还想做什么
Okay, What else do we wanna do?
我们知道这是涉及时间的问题。
We know this is involving timing.
所以如果我想说我每 10 秒就能完成这个
So if I wanna say I only want this
executed every ten seconds or
就像这样
something like that.
所以设定时间间隔是我要用的两条时间
So set interval is something I'm gonna use
because there's two ways to do timing,
设置时间间隔或设置超时。
set interval or set time out.
其实我不需要设定时间，我要设定时间。
Actually I don't want set interval,
I want set time outs.
而设定的时间将会起到一些作用，而不是这个功能。
And set time outs gonna take some
function, not this function.
关了它就得花时间
Close it off, it's going to take the time.
所以我要在这个时间里说我从这里得到的
So I'm gonna pass in this time
argument that I got from up here.
而当该时间在 10 秒或 10 秒内失效
And then once the time has
expired as in the 10 seconds or
500 毫秒或您想要的任何内容都已关闭。
500 milliseconds or
whatever you want has run down.
我想引用我原本想要的功能
I wanna invoke the function that
I was originally trying to call.
那么我们如何唤起一个功能呢 ?
So how do we evoke a function?
我们在过去的练习中学到了这一点。
We learned that in the previous exercise.
呼叫还是申请对吧
Call or apply, right?
所以当这事结束后
So when this is done,
当计时器运行的时候我想把它自己叫做功能
when the timer has run out I wanna
actually call the function itself.
我们会说 fn.apply，我们会给它这个背景，
So we'll say fn.apply, and
we'll give it the context of this,
我们会在辩论中通过这很不错的
and we'll pass in the arguments,
which is pretty good.
我可以把它放了
I could actually just leave that off.
但如果我想具体说明我可以说的话
But if I'm trying to be
specific I could say arguments.
嗯，好吧，那是什么，
Hm, okay, that's that's something,
但如果我们执行这一 debunounce 函数怎么办
but what will happen if we
execute this debounce function?
现在有什么事没有人吗
What will happen now, anybody, nobody?
没事的我知道我们现在已经解决了问题
It's okay, I know we've been
solving problems for a while now,
就像真正的触觉面试
like a real tactile interview.
是的， Ratel.
Yes, Ratel.
> > 我没有解决问题。
&gt;&gt; I didn't solve the problem.
> > 没关系的
&gt;&gt; That's okay.
这会触发五个事件，对吧 ?
&gt;&gt; [LAUGH] That's gonna fire five events,
right?
> > 嗯，它会，它会设置 5个，或者，一个，两个，三个，四个，五个。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, it will, it'll set up five,
or, one, two, three, four, five.
对五个会设定五个设定的时间
Yes, that's five,
it will set up five set timeouts,
我们会在最后的时候把火都烧了
which will at the end of the time
that we pass in will all fire.
这不是我们想要的
That's not what we want at all.
在这一点上，我们只是推迟执行这一职能。
At this point, we're just
delaying execution that function.
我们想要的是如果已经有一个功能正在被执行
What we want is if there's already
a function being executed, so
请考虑自动完成的示例。
think of the autocomplete example.
如果他们还在打字我们就不开火了
If they're still typing, we don't
wanna fire this function apply until
他们已经完成了我们想要的行动
they're finished doing
the action that we want.
然后我们就有了我们想要执行的完整的数据，然后我们就把它烧了。
And then we have the complete data that
we wanna execute on, then we fire that.
因此，正在记住设置超时设置时间间隔返回和标识。
So a way of doing that is remembering that
set timeout set interval return and ID.
所以我们会说 setTimeoutId。
So we'll say setTimeoutId.
在这个范围内我要说的是 setTimeoutId。
And in this scope,
I'm gonna say setTimeoutId.
我们要把它设置为空
We're gonna set it to null for now.
好了现在我们至少有个参考
All right, so
now we have at least a reference,
如果有什么东西在跑的话
if there's something already running.
如果有什么事我们想取消它因为那个人还在打字
And if there's something running, we wanna
cancel it because the person still typing
在此示例中，我们要取消该操作。
in this example, we wanna cancel that.
那么，如何检查 JavaScript 中是否存在某些内容 ?
So how do I check if something
exists in JavaScript?
如果 setTimeoutId ( 如果存在 ) ，那么
I say If, so if the setTimeoutId,
if it exists,
我们想取消之前的一切
we wanna cancel whatever
else was coming before.
因此，我们只需要设置一个设置，而不是设置五个设置超时。
So instead of setting five set timeouts,
we only wanna set one.
这意味着我们要取消之前的一切
That means we cancel anything
else that was before it.
所以我们要清空时间
So we're gonna clear interval.
还是间隔?
Or was it interval?
不抱歉清除超时
No, sorry, clear timeout.
如果你错了我不会惩罚你的
I wouldn't penalize you
if you got it wrong.
设置 TimeoutId。
Set TimeoutId.
好的，那么现在我们把它叫做一行的时候会发生什么呢 ?
Okay, so now what happens
when we call this in a row?
这其中一个会被处决吗
Which one of these is
going to get executed?
>> 最后一个。
&gt;&gt; The last one.
> 是的最后一个因为我们要过去了
&gt;&gt; Yes, the last one,
because we're coming through.
这是在发送超时，因此我们具有 TimeoutId。
This is we're sending a timeout,
so we have a TimeoutId.
下次我们调用这个功能时它会说有一个 TimeoutId
The next time we invoke this function
it's gonna say, there's a TimeoutId,
我要取消最后一个这样它就不会火了
I'm gonna cancel that last one so
it never fires.
就像它从未存在过一样
It's like it never existed.
这将一直持续到这个功能被调用为止。
And that's going to keep doing that
until this function is called.
但我们错过了一个重要的步骤
But there's one missing
step we need to do,
当调用此函数时会发生什么情况 ?
which is what happens when
this function is called?
>> 除去 TimeoutId。
&gt;&gt; Get rid of the TimeoutId.
>> 正好，我们需要清除 TimeoutId。
&gt;&gt; Exactly,
we need to get rid of the TimeoutId.
否则我们就会被人困在这里
Because otherwise, we're gonna get here,
and it will just be stuck,
它永远不会执行任何事情
it'll never execute anything.
所以我们会说， setTimeoutId，我们会说它等于空。
So we're just gonna say, setTimeoutId,
we'll say it's equal to null.
这就是如何实施去债务的方法。
And that's how to implement debounce.
如果你从没见过它或者想过它是如何实施的
If you've never seen it before or
thought about how it's implemented,
这有点挑战
it's a little challenging.
但一旦你看到了你就会开始思考
But once you see it,
you start to think okay,
我需要返回一个能在其他地方工作的功能。
I need to return a function that's
gonna work at some other point.
现在那是我的债务
Now that's debounce.
如果我们要实施节流，很相似的概念。
If we wanna implement throttle,
very similar concept.
除了油门我想先执行这个
Except throttle just says,
I wanna execute this first one, and
我不想在它到期之前执行任何其他的操作。
I don't wanna execute anything else that
comes after it until the time has expired.
所以，我们不排除超时，而是说如果有超时，我就会回来。
So instead of clearing the timeout, we say
if there's a timeout, I would just return.
它说，已经有东西在运行，时间还没有到期。
Cuz it's saying, there's already something
running and the time hasn't expired yet.
好吧我还是回去吧
All right cool, I'll just return.
所以这些都不会火
So none of these would fire.
这只会火
This one would fire.
所有这些都不会发生火灾，直到时间过去。
None of these would fire
until the time has elapsed.
这就是如何实施油门的方法。
And that's how to implement throttle.
你可以看到，你可以逐渐建立起一种非常强大的方法来计时事物，或者
And you see you can gradually build up
a really powerful way of timing things, or
在一定时间间隔设置事物，如果您可以实现解块或调速，或者
setting things at certain intervals, if
you can implement debounce or throttle or
就像这样
something like that.
好吧我知道如果你以前没见过这个很有挑战性
All right, I know that one was challenging
if you've never seen it before.
但现在我们希望能理解设定的时间和时间间隔
But hopefully now we understand
set timeouts and intervals and
都是些好东西
all that good stuff.